Tian Yuan

Maroubra, NSW 0488 054 288 yuantian23au@outlook.com

A Bachelor of Computer Science student at University of New South Wales working towards degree completion in May 2019. Internships and volunteer experience as a Junior Software QA Engineer, and Product Manager Assistant include testing project logic behavior, helping product managers collect analytical data, tracking project status, and testing project status to support management decisions.

Education and Qualifications

Bachelor of Computer Science Jul 2016 – Expected May 2019

University of New South Wales, Sydney

Bachelor of Telecommunication and Management Sep 2014 – Jan 2016

Peking Post and Technology University

Higher School Certificate: Beijing No.13 High School 2014

Work Experience

Junior Software QA Engineer and Product Manager Assistant (Intern)

Dec 2017 – Feb 2018

Sinopec Pcitc, Beijing

- Collected and analysed information about various cloud services, such as Ali Cloud, Baidu Cloud and Tencent Cloud
- Helped product managers collect analytical data using the PCITC system
- Tracked and tested the new system status to support management decisions

Programming Teacher (Part Time)

Dreamcodestrue, Shenzhen

May 2018 - present

- Instructing children aged 6-14 on basic coding including Python and Scratch
- Submitting a report for each student recording their learning process
- Received the Best teacher award for three consecutive months

Operations Assistant (Part Time)

Dreamcodestrue, Shenzhen

June 2018 - Aug 2018

• Helped improve the course structure

Conducted logic tests for the new system

- Designed special courses for special events, including the Halloween, Mother's Day, and Christmas Special Courses
- Created short video courses to promote the company on DouYin and YouTube
- Designed recording lessons and assisted in shooting videos of recording lessons
- Optimized the Trial Class and increased the rate of parents' purchase of Package Classes after the Trial Class

Computer Science Tutor (Part Time)

HD Education, Sydney

Jan 2019 – present

- Teaching Data Structure and Algorithm in C language
- Teaching Software Engineering fundamentals in Python language
- Teaching basic Agile Development process

Volunteer Experience

Project Hope Society

Mar 2017 - Jul 2017

Marketing Subcommittee

- Communicated with the Events Department to identify effective ways of promoting the events
- Promoted and marketed Project Hope Society by collaborating with the Events Department, and produced the video for special events
- Coordinated activities and events
- Designed and produced the posters and banners for the events

Software and Skills

- Excellent coding skills in Python, Java, C, Scratch, SQL, JS, HTML and Css
- Proficient in Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook)
- Competent in Windows and Linux based application development environment
- Competent in version control tools (Github and Bit Bucket)
- Competent in Agile Development process
- Basic knowledge in Photoshop and AE use

Project Experience

- Unsw Talk
 - Using Python flask and raw HTML CSS and Bootstrap, I created a website called Unsw talk. It was a course assignment, and there was no need to link the website on the server.
- Gridlock Rush Hour Game
 - Using java and java Swing, created an interesting puzzle solving game called Gridlock Rush Hour together with team members. There are three modes in the game and I wrote most of the frontend code.
- Church Event Management
 - Created a website called Church Event Management for the church together with team members. The back-end of the project used Django and front-end used Bootstrap, Html CSS and Jquery. I wrote all of the front-end code for this project.

Other Languages

Mandarin (native speaker) Korean (fundamental)